Milch Gallery
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Milch Gallery records
1911-1980
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Milch Gallery
38 linear feet
The records of Milch Gallery measure 38 linear feet and date from 1911-1980. Edward Milch (1865-1953) opened the Edward Milch Gallery in New York City. In 1916, he formed a partnership with his brother Albert Milch (1881-1951), a gilder and framer, creating E. & A. Milch, Inc., a gallery specializing in American art. Harold C. Milch (1904-1981), Albert's son, was appointed a partner in 1944 and continued the business until his death. Business records of Milch Gallery, 1911-1968, include correspondence, sales records, inventories, financial records, printed matter, photographs, and legal documents.
Historical Note
Between 1911 and 1916, prior to the establishment of the Milch Galleries, Austrian immigrant Edward Milch (1865-1953) operated the Edward Milch Galleries at 939 Madison Avenue 1911, mainly handling prints and providing framing services.
Albert Milch (1881-1951) was employed by a gilder and later a picture framer before becoming the business partner of his older brother. In 1916 they incorporated as E. & A. Milch (with Edward as President and Albert as Secretary of the corporation) and opened the Milch Galleries at 108 West 57th Street, New York City. During their partnership, Edward served as President and Albert as Secretary of the corporation. According to Joseph Gotlieb, a long-time employee, during this period Montross Gallery became inclined toward modern French art and the American artists associated with them began searching for galleries more sympathetic to their interests. "As Albert Milch was a framemaker to several of them, and as he was opening a new gallery in 1916 to specialize in American Art, some artists decided to let the Milch Galleries, and others, handle their work. It turned out to be a good arrangement for both sides, and a successful one" (letter from Joseph S. Gotleib to Susan Hobbs [National Museum of American Art], December 30, 1977).
From the beginning, Milch Galleries dealt in American art almost exclusively, representing living artists, handling the estates of recently deceased artists; in addition they acquired nineteenth century works for resale and accepted pieces on commission. Although framing and restoration services continued to be offered to customers, this aspect of the business soon diminished in importance.
Harold C. Milch (1904-1981), Albert's son, was affiliated with the business, and upon his father's retirement was appointed partner; after Albert died in 1951, Harold was sole proprietor, serving as both President and Secretary.
Milch Galleries moved to smaller quarters at 55 East 57th Street in 1947, and ten years later to 21 East 67th Street. In 1967, the name was changed to Milch Gallery and the business relocated to 1014 Madison Avenue. The gallery dissolved upon the death of Harold Milch. A third brother, David C. Milch, was also an art dealer, but was not associated with Milch Gallery.
Date Event
1911 Edward Milch Galleries opens at 939 Madison Ave.
1912 First exhibition at Edward Milch Galleries
1916 Incorporation of E. & A. Milch; Edward Milch, President, and Albert Milch, Secretary; change of name to Milch Galleries and relocation to 108 West 57th St.
1918 Milch Galleries Art Notes begins publication
1944 Edward Milch retires; Albert Milch President, and Harold C. Milch [son of Albert], Secretary
1947 Milch Galleries moves to 55 East 57th St.
1951 Death of Albert Milch (1881-1951); Harold C. Milch, President and Secretary
1953 Death of Edward Milch (1865-1953)
1957 Milch Galleries moves to 21 East 67th St.
1966 Archives of American Art begins acquiring records of the Milch Galleries (gifts and loans from Milch Galleries)
1967 Relocation to 1014 Madison Ave., and name change to Milch Gallery
1981 Death of Harold C. Milch (1904-1981)
1986 Archives of American Art receives the bulk of Milch Gallery records (gift of Salander-O'Reilly Galleries)
Scope and Content Note
The records of Milch Gallery document the business transactions of the corporation and the professional and personal relationships of the Milch brothers with the artists they represented, as well as with the larger community of artists and art dealers between 1911 and 1980. Unfortunately, early correspondence is sparse. In a letter responding to a 1951 request for historical information, Milch replied: "Several years ago [1947] we had to give up our gallery at 108 West 57th Street, and move to smaller quarters here. Since we had no room for old records, we had to destroy most of them."
Alphabetical files are comprised mainly of incoming correspondence from 1911 to 1962. Correspondence concerns arrangements for exhibitions, sales and consignments, advice to collectors and executors of estates, and routine business matters. A number of the artists represented in these files were friends of the Milch brothers and some of their letters mention their personal lives as well as their formal business with the Gallery. Collectors who routinely dealt with Milch Galleries included John Gellatly, Mary Blair, Hersey Egginton, Carlton Palmer, and Edward Coykendell; a three volume manuscript catalogue of Coykendell's collection is included. Among the estates handled by Milch were Willard Metcalf, John Twachtman, Abbott H. Thayer, Maurice Fromkes, and Thomas Moran.
Also found are sales records and other financial records such as general ledgers, sales and purchase records, and tax information.
Printed matter consists of gallery exhibition catalogs, checklists, invitations, announcements, publications, and scrapbooks. Many catalogs and checklists are annotated with prices and other information. A complete run of Milch Galleries Art Notes, issued intermittently from 1918-1928/29 is preserved with the gallery records. as is a scrapbook relating to early exhibitions held at the Edward Milch Galleries and E. & A. Milch, Inc., and artists represented by them.
Photographs included with the records are less voluminous than might be expected, and pictures of works of art predominate. There are also a very small number of exterior and interior photographs of Milch Gallery, photographs of people including artists, Edward and Albert Milch, and photographs of groups such as Ten American Artists and the Associated Dealers in American Paintings.
See Index for List of Milch Gallery Exhibitions and Checklists
Arrangement
Records of the Milch Gallery are organized into six series. With the exception of the alphabetical files, records are arranged by record type and then chronologically. Photographs are categorized by subject, with pictures of individuals arranged alphabetically by name, and works of art arranged alphabetically by artist.
Series 1: Alphabetical Files, 1911-1962
Series 2: Sales Records and Inventories, 1911-1969, undated
Series 3: Financial Records, 1914-1980, undated
Series 4: Printed Matter, 1996, 1910-1967, undated
Series 5: Photographs, 1903-circa 1944, undated
Series 6: Miscellaneous, 1916-1970, undated
Separated Material
In 1995 the Archives of American Art received an addition to the Milch Gallery records from Hirschl & Adler Galleries, Inc. The addition measures 0.6 linear feet and contains business correspondence; photographs of the interior of Milch Galleries from June 1959; an inventory of documents concerning the Armory Show with related correspondence that was found in the Bush-Holley House; and artist files consisting of correspondence, clippings, photographs, sales records, and printed matter for: Ralph Blakelock, Aaron Bohrod, Mary Cassatt, Arthur B. Davies, Frank Duveneck, Walt Kuhn, George Luks, Maurice Prendergast, Everett Shinn, John Sloan, and John Twachtman.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Moran, Thomas, 1837-1926
Subjects-Topical:
Art, American; Art galleries, Commercial -- New York (State) -- New York; Art -- Collectors and collecting; Painters; Gallery owners; Art dealers -- New York (State) -- New York
Types of Materials:
Gallery records; Photographs
Names:
Acheson, Alice; Adams, Charles L., 19th cent; Adams, Wayman, 1883-1959; Aiken, Charles Avery, 1872-1965; Albee, Grace; Anderson, Karl, 1874-1956; Archipenko, Alexander, 1887-1964; Appel, Marianne, 1913-; Arms, John Taylor, 1887-1953; Ascher, Mary G. (Mary Goldman), b. 1900; Azzaretti, Faust; Bacon, Peggy, 1895-1987; Baer, Martin, 1895-1961; Ballin, Hugo, 1879-1956; Barlow, Myron, 1873-1937; Barmore, Charles; Barr, Charles H.; Barr, Norman, 1908-; Barrymore, Lionel, 1878-1954; Baumann, Gustave, 1881-1971; Beal, Reynolds, 1866-1951; Bellows, George, 1882-1925; Benson, Frank Weston, 1862-1951; Biddle, George, 1885-; Blackburn, Morris, 1902-1979; Blakelock, Ralph Albert, 1847-1919; Blanch, Arnold, 1896-1968; Blanch, Lucile, 1895-1981; Bluemner, Oscar, 1867-1938; Blumenschein, Ernest Leonard, 1874-1960; Bohm, Max, 1868-1923; Bohrod, Aaron; Bosa, Louis, 1905-; Breckenridge, Hugh H. (Hugh Henry), 1870-1937; Bridgman, Frederick Arthur, 1847-1928; Browne, George Elmer, 1871-1946; Bruce, Edward, 1879-1943; Brush, George de Forest, 1855-1941; Buck, Claude, 1890-1974; Burlin, Paul, 1886-1969; Burr, George Elbert, 1859-1939; Butler, Howard Russell, 1856-1934; Calder, Alexander Stirling, 1870-1945; Carroll, John, 1892-1959; Chamberlain, Samuel, 1895-1975; Cheffetz, Asa, 1896-1965; Christy, Howard Chandler, 1873-1952; Cole, Alphaeus Philemon, 1876-1988; Congdon, William, 1912-; Crane, Bruce, 1857-1937; Curran, Charles C. (Charles Courtney), 1861-1942; Daingerfield, Elliott, 1859-1932; Davey, Randall, 1887-1964; DeCamp, Joseph, 1858-1923; De Groot, Adelaide Milton, b. 1876; Dehn, Adolf, 1895-1968; Dessar, Louis Paul, 1867-1952; Dewing, Thomas Wilmer, 1851-1938; Diederich, William Hunt, 1884-1953; Dike, Phil, 1906-1990; Donoho, Gaines Ruger, 1857-1916; Du Bois, Guy Pène, 1884-1958; Duncan, Charles, b. 1892; Eakins, Susan Macdowell; Etnier, Stephen, 1903-1984; Farnsworth, Jerry, 1895-1982; Fechin, Nikolai Ivanovich, 1881-1955; Fenton, Beatrice, 1887-1983; Fitzgerald, James, 1899-1971; Flagg, James Montgomery, 1877-1960; Fredenthal, David, 1914-1958; French, Daniel Chester, 1850-1931; Fuchs, Emil, 1866-1929; Gallagher, Sears, 1869-1955; Ganso, Emil, 1895-1941; Gaspard, Leon, 1882-1964; Genth, Lillian Mathilde, 1876-1953; Gonzalez, Xavier, 1898-1993; Greenwood, Marion, 1909-1970; Gregory, John, 1879-1958; Gregory, Waylande, 1905-1971; Grosz, George, 1893-1959; Halpert, Samuel, 1884-1930; Hart, George Overbury, 1868-1933; Hartmann, Sadakichi, 1867-1944; Haskell, Ernest, 1876-1925; Hassam, Childe, 1859-1935; Heerman, Norbert Leo, b. 1891; Heinz, Charles, 1885-1955; Hennings, E. Martin, 1886-1956; Henri, Robert, 1865-1929; Hopkinson, Charles, 1869-1962; Ireland, Leroy, 1889-1970; Judson, Alice, d. 1948; Kalish, Max, 1891-1945; Katz, A. Raymond (Alexander Raymond), 1895-1974; Kingman, Dong, 1911-; Kroll, Leon, 1884-1974; Kronberg, Louis, 1872-1965; Kupferman, Lawrence, 1909-1982; Laufman, Sidney, 1891-; Lawson, Ernest, 1873-1939; Lever, Hayley, 1876-1958; Lie, Jonas, 1880-1940; Linde, Ossip L.; Low, Will Hicok, 1853-1932; Lucioni, Luigi, 1900-; Lutz, Dan, 1906-; MacRae, Emma Fordyce, 1887-1974; Manship, Paul, 1885-1966; Melchers, Gari, 1860-1932; Metcalf, Willard Leroy, 1858-1925; Meyerowitz, William, 1887-1981; Milch, Albert, 1881-1951; Milch, Edward, 1865-1954; Moffett, Ross; Mora, F. Luis (Francis Luis), 1874-1940; Moran, Thomas, 1837-1926; Murphy, Hermann Dudley, 1867-1945; Murphy, John Francis, 1853-1921; Myers, Jerome, 1867-1940; Nagler, Edith, b. 1890; Oberteuffer, Karl, 1908-; Ochtman, Leonard, 1854-1934; Parshall, DeWitt, 1864-1956; Pearson, Ralph M., 1883-1958; Perrine, Van Dearing, 1868 or 9-1955; Pittman, Hobson, 1900-1972; Pleissner, Ogden M.; Pollet, Joseph, 1897-1979; Pousette-Dart, Nathaniel, 1886-1965; Pugh, Mabel, b. 1891; Redfield, Edward Willis, 1869-1965; Ritschel, William, 1864-1949; Romano, Umberto, 1906-; Rungius, Carl, 1869-1959; Ryder, Chauncey F., 1868-1949; Ryerson, Margery; Sample, Paul, 1896-1974; Sawyer, Wells, 1863-1960; Schofield, Walter Elmer, 1867-1944; Shuster, Will; Shapiro, David, 1916-; Sharp, Joseph Henry, 1859-1953; Sheets, Millard, 1907-; Speicher, Eugene E. (Eugene Edward), 1883-1962; Speight, Francis, 1896-; Sterne, Maurice, 1878-1957; Sterner, Albert, 1863-1946; Tanner, Henry Ossawa, 1859-1937; Thayer, Abbott Handerson, 1849-1921; Trebilcock, Paul, 1902-1981; Tryon, Dwight William, 1849-1925; Twachtman, John Henry, 1853-1902; Ufer, Walter, 1876-1936; Varian, Dorothy, 1895-1987; Vonnoh, Robert William, 1858-1933; Warneke, Heinz (Heinrich), 1895-1983; Watkins, Franklin Chenault, 1894-1972; Waugh, Frederick Judd, 1861-1940; Weir, John F. (John Ferguson), b. 1841; Weir, Julian Alden, 1852-1919; White, Henry Cooke, 1861-1952; Wickey, Harry; Wiggins, Carleton, 1848-1932; Wiles, Irving Ramsay, 1861-1948; Woodward, Robert Strong, 1885-1957; Woodward, Stanley Wingate, b. 1890; Wyeth, Andrew, 1917-; Zucker, Jacques, 1900-; Milch Galleries; E. & A. Milch, Inc
Provenance
Milch Gallery gave the Archives of American Art a small selection of correspondence, photographs, and printed matter, and loaned a few other items in 1966-1967; these records were microfilmed on reels D285, N730, and NM1-NM2. Records of the Milch Gallery were purchased from the estate of Harold C. Milch by Elliott Galleries of New York City, and subsequently acquired by Salander-O'Reilly Galleries, which donated them to the Archives in 1986. With the exception of the scrapbook about Thomas Moran (reel N730; present location of the original is unknown), prior loans and gifts from Milch Gallery were incorporated and refilmed with the 1986 gift.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Patrons must use microfilm copy.
Alternative Forms Available
The bulk of the collection is microfilmed on reels #4410-4465; earlier loans were filmed on reels D285, N730, and NM1-NM2.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Alphabetical Files, 1911-1962, Series 1:
  This series contains mainly incoming correspondence including itemized invoices, receipts, catalogues of private collections, estate inventories, and printed matter and manuscript checklists, and other items enclosed with correspondence. Carbon copies of replies are sparse, but the reverse sides of many letters contain drafts of replies or brief notes to the secretary indicating the desired response. Correspondence concerns arrangements for exhibitions, sales and consignments, advice to collectors and executors of estates, and routine business matters. For each file range a list of selected correspondents, including artists, is provided. Other records in the series of alphabetical files include itemized invoices, receipts, catalogs of private collections, estate inventories, printed items, manuscript checklists, and other items enclosed with correspondence.
  - A-American Federation of Arts (Reel 4410)
    Acheson, Alice
    Adams, Charles L.
    Adams, Wayman
    Addams, Clifford
    Aiken, Charles A.
    Albee, Grace
    Alden, Henri Vere
  - American Federation of Arts-Bing (Reel 4411)
    American Federation of Arts
    Anderson, Karl
    Ansbacher, Jessie
    Anthony, Elizabeth M.
    Archipenko, Alexander
    Appel, Marianne
    Arms, John Taylor
    Ascher, Mary
    Azzaretti, Faust
    Bacon, Peggy
    Baer, Martin
    Bailey, Merrill
    Baker, Joan
    Barker, George
    Ball, Ellen Lee
    Ballin, Hugo
    Barbarie, James
    Barlow, Myron
    Barmore, Charles
    Barr, Charles H.
    Barr, Norman
    Barrymore, Lionel
    Bartlett, Dana
    Bates, Kenneth
    Baumann, Gustave
    Bayard, Clifford A.
    Beach, Howard D.
    Beal, Reynolds
    Beauchamp, John
    Beaugureau, Francis H.
    Behrent, Robert H.
    Bellows, George
    Bennett, Francis I.
    Benson, Frank W.
    Bentley, Lester W.
    Berge, Henry
    Berge, Stephens
    Berman, Saul
    Bewley, Murray Percival
    Biddle, George
  - Birmingham Museum-Brush (Reel 4412)
    Birmingham Museum
    Blackburn, Morris
    Blagden, Thomas
    Blakelock, Ralph
    Blanch, Arnold,
    Blanch, Lucille
    Blondheim, Adolphe
    Blound, Barbara Boyd
    Bluemner, Oscar
    Blum, Edith
    Blumenschein, Ernest L.
    Bogert, George H.
    Boogar, William F.
    Bohm, Max
    Bohrod, Aaron
    Borgord, Martin
    Bosa, Louis
    Bower, Alexander
    Boyd, Byron B.
    Brackman, Robert
    Braun, Maurice
    Breckenridge, Hugh
    Bridgeman, Frederick
    Britton, Harry
    Britton, James
    Brown, Frank
    Brown, Pamela
    Brown, Pluma
    Browne, George Elmer
    Browne, Matilda [Mrs. Frederick Van Wyck]
    Bruce, Edward
    Brush, George deForest
  - Brush-California Palace (Reel 4413)
    Buchanan, Charles L.
    Buck, Claude
    Burchess, Arnold
    Burgdorff, Ferdinand
    Burlin, Paul
    Burns, Paul C.
    Burrn, George E.
    Butler, Andrew R.
    Butler, Howard Russell
    Calder, A. Stirling
    Caldwell, Brown
  - California Palace-Chase (Reel 4414)
    Callcott, Frank
    Cameron-Merk, Hazel
    Cantine, Jo
    Carlisle, Mary H.
    Carlson, John
    Carroll, John
    Carter, Whitford
    Cary, William M.
    Castigan, John E.
    Cavacos, Emmanuel A.
    Carutti-Simmons, Teresa
    Chabot, Joseph
    Chamberlain, Samuel
    Chann, George
    Chase, Marion M.
  - Chase-Coykendell (Reel 4415)
    Cheffetz, Asa
    Christy, Howard Chandler
    Clark, Elsie Southwick
    Clark, Roland
    Clymer, J. F.
    Cohen, Max
    Cole, Alphaeus P.
    Colman, Blanche E.
    Colman, Keith
    Colman, Ruth
    Comfort, Barbara
    Conacher, John
    Congdon, William G.
    Cooper, Margaret
    Coughlin, Mildred
    Coulter, Mary
    Couper, J. S. [Mrs. B. King]
    Cox, Charles M.
  - Coykendell-Drew (Reel 4416)
    Crane, Bruce
    Crespi, Pachita
    Curran, Charles C.
    Dah, Hermann M.
    Daingerfield, Elliott
    Davey, Randall
    Davidson, Allan A.
    Dawson, Arthur
    Day, Francis
    Dearth, Henry G.
    De Camp, Joseph
    De Forest, Julie Morrow (See also: Julie Mathilde Morrow)
    De Groot, Adelaide
    Dehn, Adolph
    Dehner, Walt
    Dellenbaugh, F. S.
    De Maine, Harry
    Deruzinsky, Gleb
    Dessar, Louis Paul
    Dewing, Thomas Wilmer
    Dickinson, Sidney E.
    Diederich, Hunt
    Di Gioia, Frank
    Dike, Phil
    Dodge, William De Leftwich
    Dohanos, Stevan
    Donoho, Roger
  - Drew-Field (Reel 4417)
    Du Bois, Guy Pene
    Du Mond, Helen S.
    Duncan, Charles S.
    Dunton, W. Herbert
    Dustin, Silas
    Eakins, Susan [Mrs. Thomas Eakins]
    Eddy, Sarah J.
    Edwards, George Wharton
    Erdmann, Richard F.
    Esten, Thomas
    Etherington, Rhea
    Etnier, Stephen M.
    Fagnani, Joseph
    Farley, Richard Blossom
    Farnsworth, Jerry (See also: Helen Sawyer [Mrs. Farnsworth])
    Fassett, Truman
    Fausett, Lynn
    Fechin, Nicholai
    Fenton, Beatrice
    Ferne, Hortense
    Field, Lester
  - Field-Gill (Reel 4418)
    Fitzgerald, James
    Flagg, J. Montgomery
    Florian, Gordon W.
    Fosdick, J. William
    Foster, Willet
    Frankl, Walter H.
    Fransioli, Thomas A.
    Franzen, August
    Fredenthal, David
    Frederick, Millie Bruhl
    Freiman, Robert J.
    French, Daniel Chester
    Frismuth, Harriet W.
    Fromkes, Maurice
    Fuchs, Emil
    Gaertner, Otta
    Gagnon, Clarence A.
    Gallagher, Sears
    Ganso, Emil
    Garber, Daniel
    Gare, Calvin
    Gaspard, Leon
    Gee, Yun
    Genth, Lilian
    Gilbert, Guy
    Gilchrist, William W.
  - Gillespie-Hanna (Reel 4419)
    Girard, Anna
    Gluckmann, Grigory
    Godwin, Frank
    Goethe, Joseph
    Golden, Richard Davis
    Gonzalez, Xavier
    Goodwin, Arthur C.
    Gray, Mary
    Green, Florence Topping
    Green, James
    Greenbowe, F. Douglas
    Greene, Jack
    Greenwood, Marion
    Gregory, John
    Gregory, Wayland
    Griswold, Verma del
    Grossman, Edwin Booth
    Grossman, Elia M.
    Grosz, George
    Gummo, Blanchard
    Hall, Frederick
    Halow, E. J.
    Halpert, Samuel
    Hamilton, Wilbert Dean
    Hammond, Ruth
  - Hanna-Horn (Reel 4420)
    Hansen, Armin
    Hart, George O.
    Hart, William H.
    Hartman, Sadakichi
    Haskell, Ernest
    Hassam, Childe
    Haswell, Ernest B.
    Heaney, Charles E.
    Heerman, Norbert
    Heil, Charles Emile
    Heinz, Charles L.
    Henderson, William P.
    Hennings, E. Martin
    Henri, Robert
    Higgins, Victor
    Hill, Alice Stanton
    Hill, Arthur Turnbull
    Hill, Polly Knipp
    Hiraga, Kamesuke
    Hirschfeld, Albert
    Hitchcock, George
    Hodgin, Marston Dean
    Hoffman, Henry L.
    Hofman, H. O.
    Holzhauer, Emil
    Hopkinson, Charles
  - Horn-Kilton (Reel 4421)
    Hornby, Lester
    Houston, Nora
    Howe, William H.
    Howell, Felicie
    Hussa, Theodore
    Hutchins, Frank Townsend
    Hutty, Alfred
    Inglis, John J.
    Ireland, Leroy
    Irvine, Wilson
    Isenburger, Eric
    Jackson, Esther
    James, Frederick
    Johansen, John C.
    Joahnson, Arthur C.
    Jones, Francis C.
    Judson, Alice
    Kalish, Max
    Kappel, Philip
    Kapustin, Razel
    Katz, A. Raymond
    Katz, Ethel
    Kerr, Gerta
  - Kilton-Lester (Reel 4422)
    Kimball, Richard
    King, Clinton
    King, Paul
    Kingman, Dong
    Klitgaard, Georgia
    Kroll, Leon
    Krongerg, Louis
    Kupferman, lawrence
    Kutchin, Lucius
    Lack, Richard F.
    Lamar, Julian
    Landers, Bertha
    Lasky, Bessie
    Lathrop, Ida Pulis
    Laufman, Sidney
    Lawrence, W. Goadby
    Lawson, Ernest
  - Lester-Melchers (Reel 4423)
    Lever, R. Hayley
    Lewis, Jessie Voss
    Lie, Jonas
    Linde, Ossip
    Lindemuth, Arlington
    Llopis, C. R.
    Lopp, H. L.
    Lord, Harriet
    Loring, William
    Low, Mary Fairchild
    Low, Will H.
    Lucioni, Luigi
    Luneau, O. J.
    Lutz, Dan
    MacColl, E. Chase
    McCouch, Gordon M.
    McCreary, Carolin
    McCutcheon, George Barr
    McDonald, William P.
    McElvoy, Michael M.
    MacNicol, Roy
    MacNutt, Glenn Gordon
    MacRae, Emma Fordyce
    Malcolm, Thalia
    Magni, Riccardo
    Manship, John
    Manship, Paul
    Mase, Carolyn C.
    Mason, Roy M.
    Mattison, Donald
    Maurice, Eleanore
    Mayer, Henrik M.
    Melchers, Gari
  - Melchers- Metcalfe (Reel 4424)
    Mendelowitz, Dan
    Metcalf Estate: miscellaneous correspondence; taxes, 1925-1940; legal documents; ledger, 1925-1926; investments, 1934-1945; bills; and bank records, 1928-1929)
    Henrietta Metcalf [widow]: bills, 1936-1943
    Addison Metcalf [son]: taxes, 1930-1943; investments, 1939-1943; financial services, 1941-1943; bills, 1941-1943; and bank records, 1941-1944
    Addison and Rosalind Metcalf: financial statement, 1941
  - Rosalind Metcalf [daughter], 1932-1946 (Reel 4424-4425)
    (taxes, 1932-1943; investments, 1937-1946; financial services, 1941-1946; and bank records, 1937-1946)
  - Metcalf-Meyerowitz (Reel 4425)
    Correspondence between Milch and Metcalf Family, Financial Matters, 1934-1962, undated
    Meyerowitz, William
  - Milch-Norton (Reel 4426)
    Millar, Addison
    Miller, Richard E.
    Moffett, Ross
    Molarsky, Maurice
    Montgomery, Edmund
    Mora, F. Luis
    Moran, Thomas
    Morang, Alfred
    Moreing, David Burr
    Morgan, Lucy C.
    Morgan, Wallace
    Morrow, Julie Mathilde (See also: Julie Morrow De Forest)
    Mott-Smith, May
    Muller, Dan
    Munsell, Richard
    Murphy, Hermann Dudley
    Murphy, J. Francis
    Myers, Jerome
    Nagler, Edith
    Nason, Thomas W.
    Neilson, Winthrop
    Newking, Natalie
    Nichols, Hobart
    Nicodemus, Chester R.
    Nisbet, Robert H.
    Noble, John
    Noecker, Harold
  - Norton-Pittman (Reel 4427)
    Nuhfer, Olive H.
    Oberteuffer, Karl
    Octman, Leonard
    O'Hara, Eliot
    Olinsky, Ivan G.
    Osborn, Frank C.
    Osk, Roselle
    Palmer, Allen I.
    Palmer, Walter L.
    Parkman, Polly